all right today's film Joe and Julie -
好吧今天的电影乔和朱莉-
okay how about this Joe and Julie the
还好这个乔和朱莉 如何
sequel okay okay how about this Joe and
续集好吧好吧乔和这个怎么样
Julie sanctification I can't like I
朱莉成圣我不能喜欢我
thank you though all right well in this
谢谢你，尽管这很好
hour we're going to take a look at the
小时我们要去看看
middle in the conclusion of John Street
在约翰街结束的中间
counseling Joe and Julie just to kind of
咨询乔和朱莉只是为了那种
set the stage as a reminder we're going
把舞台作为我们要去的提醒
to take a look at a three minute clip
看一下三分钟的片段
from session 1 that you saw about a
从第1节你看到的
month ago but this will kind of set the
一个月前， 但这将设置
stage and remind us all of the serious
阶段并提醒我们所有的严重
presenting problems that there are in
提出存在的问题
this case so here's our first selection
这种情况所以这是我们的第一个选择
of the day me like she has never even
那天我像她甚至从来没有
you know studied the Bible recently just
你知道最近刚刚研究过圣经
the way she acts and behaves or doesn't
她的行为和行为方式
seem to be any connection there of a
似乎与a的任何联系
biblical truth and how she's living her
圣经真理以及她如何生活在她身上
life on discipline just over sleeping
纪律的生活就在睡觉
anger and even just a overwhelming
愤怒，甚至只是压倒一切
sadness and a sense of kind of loathsome
悲伤和一种令人厌恶的感觉
somberness that look it's just hard to
黯淡，看上去它只是很难
understand when the you know just read
了解你刚认识的时候
the Psalms and you can be so encouraged
诗篇，你可以这么鼓励
and and I think it's just really I don't
并且我认为我真的没有
know what to do you know we've tried a
知道该怎么做你知道我们已经尝试过了
number of different things I've tried to
我试过的不同事物的数量
get her some some counseling from one of
给她一些咨询
the elders why is in our church and and
长辈为什么在我们的教会和
that lasted for a few weeks and you know
持续了几个星期，你知道
maybe some helpful things came out of
也许有些有用的东西出来了
that just another friend in the church
那只是教堂里的另一个朋友
but she's still the same there hasn't
但她仍然存在有不一样的
seem to be any real substantial change
似乎是任何真正的重大变化
that has been continuous it's been just
这一直是持续的
little bits and pieces there but it's
那里有点点零碎但是它
always been reverting back into the same
一直在恢复原状
patterns
模式
Joe I need to ask you this question and
乔·我要问你这个问题，
I don't want you to answer it twice not
我不想让你回答这个问题两次不
well what's the word I want to use I
那么我想用的是什么呢？
don't want you to answer it real quickly
不希望你快速回答它
without thought but do you really love
没有想过， 但你真的爱
Julie yeah she is
朱莉，是的，她是
she was my joy she's the one that I
她是我的喜悦， 她就是我
think about constantly and since the
想约不断，并且由于
first day I said eyes upon her she was
第一天，我说她是她的眼睛
the girl of my dreams that if had the
我梦中的女孩，如果有
qualities that I wanted to seeing my
我希望看到我的品质
wife yeah and you know at the same time
老婆啊，你知道在同一时间
I I have to admit that just the great
我必须承认，只有伟大的
responsibilities in ministry and and
在事工和职责中的责任
caring for her sometimes can sometimes
有时可以照顾她
can muffle that kind of expression of
可以掩盖那种表达
love that I really desire to show her it
喜欢我真的希望向她展示它
times in the kind of care and compassion
在那种关心和同情的时代
that I think are important there and I'm
我觉得那里很重要而且我很重要
still I feel like this is more for me in
我仍然觉得这是更适合我
some ways because I'm struggling really
某些方面，因为我真的在挣扎
with how to you know how to handle my
如何知道如何处理我的
own yeah sense of responsibility and and
拥有是的责任感和
unworthiness and discipline and part of
不值得和纪律和部分
me is what I'm studying I feel like I'm
我就是我正在学习的我觉得我是
neglecting her because I'm not spending
因为我没有花钱而忽略了她
time with her and when I'm spending time
和她在一起的时间以及我花时间的时间
with her I feel this tension of life
和她在一起，我感受到了生活的紧张
should be preparing for my next sermon
应该为我的下一篇讲道做准备
or preparing for next counselling
或准备下一次咨询
session and there's this constant battle
会议，这是不断的战斗
back and forth
来回
well that was memorable wasn't it Wow
那令人难忘的不是哇
well in as a biblical counsellor in
作为圣经的辅导员
cases like this sessions like that you
喜欢这样的会话就像你一样
realize the magnitude of the problem you
意识到你的问题 的严重性
realize the difficulty of the depression
意识到抑郁的困难
and you also realize the need for the
你也意识到需要
husband here to understand some
老公在这里了解一些
important things about his role as a
关于他作为一个角色的重要事项
husband and his ministry to his wife so
丈夫和他的事工对他的妻子如此
there's a lot that goes on and often
经常会有很多事情发生
with a couple there are two different
和一对夫妻有两种不同
things going on with a husband and the
事情发生的事情与丈夫和
wife and each require the biblical
妻子和每个人都需要圣经
solution and
解决方案和
really in some parts of it it's the
真的在它的某些部分它是
caring communication of the truce of
关心休战的关怀沟通
hope and then the other side it's the
希望，然后另一方是它
confrontation of sin from God's Word so
从上帝的话语中对抗罪恶
very complex as a biblical counsellor
作为圣经辅导员非常复杂
it's just a wonderful adventure with God
这只是与上帝的奇妙冒险
though because you are you're praying
虽然因为你在祈祷
diligently for each council Lee you are
努力为每个理事会利你
praying for God's direction and for your
祈求上帝的方向和你的方向
studies and then you're working very
研究然后你工作得非常好
hard at looking at your notes reviewing
很难看你的笔记审查
all the information you have from the
你从掌握的信息
homework so that you can understand as
做作业让你可以理解为
clearly as possible what's going on in
尽可能清楚地发生了什么
the heart of each Council II and then
每个理事会的核心II然后
from there you're seeking to answer the
你从那里寻求回答
question what does the Bible say about
质疑圣经说的是什么
that and then you consider with the Lord
然后你考虑与主
what's the best way to communicate these
什么是沟通这些的最佳方式
truths to these people at this time well
这个时候这些人的真相很好
now we're going to move to session 4 and
现在我们要转到第4节和第4节
this is a part that we haven't seen yet
这是我们还没有看到的一部分
here so we're in session for it's three
在这里，所以我们正在讨论它的三个
weeks since what we saw there some
我们在那里见到了一些星期
change has begun some things have have
一些事情已经开始改变
started to happen between each of the
开始每个之间发生
council Lee's and the Lord and the
理事会李和主和和
caring counselor has had a part in that
关怀顾问参与其中
so we move ahead to a section in session
所以我们继续前进到会议的一个部分
for I know I remember in that second
因为我知道我记得那一秒
session when you came back after we I
在我们之后你回来的时候
give me a first assignment and how much
给我一个第一个任务和多少
of a struggle it was for you to read
你要读的是一场斗争
those early chapters of the book and how
这本书的前几章和如何
you had to do it over and over again but
你必须一遍又一遍地做，但是
I remember how we talked about
我记得我们是如何谈论的
perseverance and the first we we went
坚持不懈，我们去的第一个
over there to Romans 15:4 we talked
在那里我们谈到罗马书15：4
about through perseverance and
通过坚持不懈和
encouragement in the scriptures we might
我们可能会鼓励经文
have hope that's where I've been zeroing
希望这是我一直在归零的地方
in with you in terms of perseverance and
和你一起坚持不懈
seeing your faith and your trust in
看到你的信仰和你的信任
Jesus Christ work itself out and things
耶稣基督自己出去做事
like this just completing your
像这样只是完成你的
responsibilities so and it's beginning
责任所以它开始了
to pay off so alright tell me what
还清这么好吗告诉我是什么
happened here I think this is the
发生在这里我认为这是
chapter and in the book about yea
关于是的章节和书中
self-pity right yeah I'm feeling sorry
自怜对，对，我感到很抱歉
for yourself yes yes it was a good
对你自己是的，这是一个很好的
chapter um
章嗯
Balthus some basic things first just it
巴尔蒂斯一些基本的东西最初只是它
was encouraging when they went through
他们经历的时候很鼓舞人心
biblical examples of or when when the
圣经中的例子或什么时候的
author went through biblical examples of
作者经历了圣经中的例子
why of people in the Bible that
为什么圣经中的人呢
struggled with feeling sorry for
为感到遗憾而苦苦挣扎
themselves or you know questioning
他们自己或你知道质疑
basically boiling it down to questioning
基本上把它归结为质疑
God and why me why is this happening to
上帝为什么我为什么会这样来
me
我
there's Elijah and I mean he had the
有以利亚， 我的意思是他有
highest high and then heat right after
之后最高，然后加热
that he had the the lowest low and that
他有最低的低和
it's encouraging to think through I
通过我思考是令人鼓舞的
hadn't thought about it in that light
没有想到这一点
before mm-hmm but just talking about I
在mm-hmm之前，但只是谈论我
guess I've always I've come at it from
我猜我总是来自它
that angle why me what what's happening
这个角度为什么我发生了什么
to me and I think this whole chapter has
对我而言，我认为整章都有
been really good at exposing just how
真的善于揭露如何
much I'm I'm focused on myself hopefully
很多，我希望自己能够专注于自己
and I mean even when I was meeting with
我的意思是即使在我见面的时候
the psychiatrist there were some things
精神科医生有一些事情
that they pointed out that were true and
他们指出，这是真的，并
interesting in I felt as if I was more
有趣的是我感觉好像我更多
informed but it just still very
告知但它仍然非常
miserable and I think just reading
悲惨，我想只是阅读
through this chapter um that was one of
通过这一章，这是其中之一
the main things I realized was and here
我意识到的主要事情就是这里
it says just to quote it was one thing
它只是引用它是一回事
that really hit me instead of asking why
这真的打击了我，而不是问为什么
we should be asking now that this has
我们现在应该问这个问题
happened how should I handle it in what
碰巧我应该怎样处理它
should my response to the situation be
我应该对这种情况做出回应吗？
yeah and that jumped out at me because I
是的， 因为我，我跳了出来
think for the last six months or
想想最近六个月或
something it's been it's I've been
这件事是我去过的
focused on myself and what you know how
专注于自己和你知道如何
how this affects me and and then it says
它如何影响我，然后它说
over here instead of why me we should be
在这里，而不是为什么我们应该
focusing instead on what God says in his
转而关注上帝在他的话语中所说的话
word about responding and handling our
关于回应和处理我们的问题
problems in
问题
you know do you think that you're doing
你知道你认为你正在做的
that better now I do I feel like I am I
现在我做得更好我觉得我就是我
think yeah and I mean he kept going on
想是的，我的意思是，他坚持下来了上
to say talking about self-pity because
说 因为自怜而 谈论
of just even the reasons why we do that
甚至是我们这样做的原因
and and then I explained me as well as
然后我解释了我以及
far as just simply exaggerating the
只是简单地夸大了
extent of your of your own problems and
你自己的问题和程度
I thought that that goes along with the
我认为， 与随之而来
question why me where usually when I ask
问我为什么通常在我问的时候
that question to myself I'm you know
那个问题对我自己我是你知道的
also thinking how big my problem is and
还在想我的问题有多大
how awful it isn't it kind of bills in
多么糟糕的不是它的账单
my own mind is and I you know and he
我自己的想法是，我知道，他
gave the example about Rachel and how
举了一个关于雷切尔的例子以及如何做
she you know had everything that she
她知道她拥有的一切
really could desire and yet she wanted
真的可以渴望，但她想要
more and she wasn't content with what
更多，她不满足于什么
the Lord provided and and she actually
主提供了，而她实际上
wanted to die when she got to that point
她到达那一点时想死
that she was so consumed with her own
她被她自己所吞噬
view on her own trials and things me
查看她自己的考验和事情
good so yeah that was that was huge good
好， 所以是的，那是非常好的
alright this is a I think this is
好吧这是我认为的
striking at a core issue for you and I
为你和我打一个核心问题
actually want to spend a little bit of
其实想花一点点
time and go into this more in depth here
时间进入这个更深入这里
in this session anything else in that
在这个会话中的任何其他内容
chapter before we got away from it hmm
在我们离开之前的一章 嗯
just just kind of more of the same I
只是我的一点点
mean then there's an example of David
那意味着有一个大卫的例子
and how he was exaggerating that the you
以及他如何夸大你的意思
know how wonderful the world and other
知道如何美妙的世界 ，其他
people have it compared to his own
与他自己相比，人们拥有它
circumstances and then switching gears
情况然后切换齿轮
to just saying that some earth or
只是说一些地球或
proverbs 3 that talks about the value of
谚语3讲述的价值
wisdom and how our prophet in her gain
智慧和我们的先知如何获得
is much more precious than jewels and in
比珠宝和更珍贵
just the understanding that and here
只是使大家认识到，在这里
says the psalmist was filling star
诗篇作者说是星星
for himself because he misunderstood the
对他自己，因为他误解了
nature of God's prosperity and you know
你知道，上帝的繁荣本质
you're simply anxious and you're simply
你只是焦虑而且你很简单
friendly because the focus is on myself
友好，因为重点是我自己
rather than on I mean the Lord and I
而不是我的意思是主和我
think that was the overarching theme of
认为这是最重要的主题
the chapter yeah yeah good you know we I
章是啊是啊你知道我们
think we can safely say it's the baby
我们可以安全地说这是宝贝
moving yeah I think that we can safely
移动是啊我认为我们可以安全
say that what the world does in trying
说，这个世界在努力做
to deal with the problem is you face it
处理问题是你面对的问题
is they try to think seek for the
他们是否试图去寻求
feelings of happiness the feelings of
感受幸福的感受
joy in and of itself which in and of
喜悦和在其本身
itself becomes a very selfish quest all
本身成为一种非常自私的追求所有
right where God says it's not in
在上帝说它不在的地方
achieving or trying to aim at the goal
实现或试图瞄准目标
of happiness that is the key for the
幸福是关键
believer it's being selfless and serving
相信它是无私和服务的
God and that the result or byproduct of
上帝和那个结果或副产品
that is a joyful life right all right in
这是一个快乐的生活没事的
fact if you have your Bible real quick I
事实上，如果你有快速的圣经我
want to show that to you go over to John
想要告诉你去约翰
13 just for a moment and then we'll I
13 只是片刻，然后我们会
want to jump back here to Joe and deal
我想回到乔和交易
with the what you've been studying
与你一直在研究的东西
together as a couple and trusting God
作为一对夫妻，相信上帝
but John 13 17 this is after Jesus has
但约翰福音13章17这是在耶稣之后
washed the disciples feet and in doing
洗了门徒脚，做了
so at this particular point in the story
所以在故事的这个特定点上
the disciples don't know who this is but
门徒不知道这是谁
Jesus has reminded them that somebody's
耶稣提醒他们有人
going to go and betray them and he says
他说要去背叛他们
in verse 17 of John 13 he says if you
在约翰福音13章第17节他说如果你
know these things and the word if there
知道这些事情和那个词
is a with the indicative meaning that
具有指示性意义的是
they did know these things if you know
如果你知道，他们确实知道这些事情
these things you are blessed if and this
这些东西， 如果 你这样， 你是幸运的
is a different if now in the Greek
如果现在在希腊语中是一个不同的
language it is a conditional clause with
语言它是一个条件子句
less certainty there if you do them and
如果你这样做，那就不那么确定了
now our tendency is to begin to think
现在我们倾向于开始思考
lord make me feel better make me feel
领主让我感觉更好让我感受到
more blessed and then I'll do the right
更加幸福，然后我会做对的
thing
事情
and God says no that's not the way it
上帝说不，那不是它的方式
works you're getting the cart before the
你工作之前就得到了推车
horse what you your biblical
马你的圣经是什么
responsibility is to do that what you
责任就是做你自己
know is right and then the good feelings
知道是对的，然后是好的感受
come then the blessings come if you wait
如果你等了，祝福来了
until you feel like doing it it'll never
直到你想要这样做它永远不会
happen more seldom will ever happen
恰巧更很少将不会发生
you've got to do that what you know is
你必须做你知道的事情
right which is really a selfless quest
这是一个无私的追求
it is it's something where I know I'm
这是我知道的事情
here to serve God whether I feel like
无论我是否愿意，都在这里为上帝服务
serving him or not I know that I'm here
为他服务与否我知道我在这里
ultimately to find my greatest joy and
最终找到我最大的快乐和
if we can say it pleasure in serving God
如果我们能说服侍上帝的乐趣
not in serving myself then this becomes
没有为自己服务，那就变成了
my quest that's what I want to do and
我的追求就是我想要做的事情
then even if I don't feel like it or not
即使我不喜欢它
even if the byproduct of it
即使它的副产品
I don't instantly feel like I'm not
我不会立刻觉得我不是
depressed anymore
郁闷了
no I have a I have a responsibility to
不，我有责任
do what I know is right and then let God
做我所知道的是正确的，然后让上帝
bless as he so determines how to bless
祝福， 因为他决定如何祝福
me
我
but this whole idea that seems to be a
但这整个想法似乎是一个
part of the world as my man's ideas that
作为我个人的想法，世界的一部分
try to achieve happiness the reason why
努力实现幸福的原因
the world is so quick to buy into
世界如此迅速地进入市场
psychotropic drugs in order to resolve
精神药物才能解决
these kind of problems it's a quick fix
这些问题是一个快速解决方案
and really what it really ends up doing
而且它到底真正结束了什么
is we've talked about earlier it really
是我们前面谈到它真的
ends up medicating you with the symptoms
最后用症状治疗你
not dealing with the real source issues
没有处理真正的源问题
that are a part of your heart and once
这是你的心脏的一部分，一旦
the medication rolls on wears off then
药物滚动然后消失
you're still back to where you were
你还是回到了原来的位置
again now true medicine addresses the
现在再次真正的医学解决了
source of the problem it cures a disease
它治愈疾病的问题的根源
but this is not true medicine what this
但这不是真正的医学这个
is more in the category of a lot of
更多的是在很多类别中
psychotropic drugs are are really almost
精神药物真的差不多了
like anesthesia I mean it's like
像麻醉，我的意思是它
somebody who's sitting on a tack and you
有人和你一起坐在大头钉上
give them an anesthesia they feel a
给他们麻醉他们感觉到
whole lot better but it doesn't
整体好多了， 但事实并非如此
necessarily mean that their problem is
一定意味着他们的问题是
gone they still have the problem so
他们仍然有问题
this is good you're getting in a
这对你来说很好
scripture you're understanding what
经文你明白了什么
needs to happen and we talked about this
需要发生，我们谈论这个
earlier there in first corinthians 10:13
早些时候在哥林多前书10:13
there is no temptation taking you except
除了以外没有诱惑
for what is common to man and God is
因为人类和上帝的共同点是
faithful
可信
all right in other words this is not
好吧，换句话说，这不是
unusual there are but other Christians
不同寻常的是其他基督徒
who have faith the same thing that Jill
谁有信心和吉尔一样的信仰
and Julia faced here in this situation
朱莉娅在这种情况下面对这里
and they've been able to face it
他们已经能够面对它了
successfully and got it they find out in
成功并得到它，他们发现了
the midst of that God is faithful he
在他中间，上帝是忠诚的
will not let you be tempted beyond what
不会让你被诱惑超越什么
you're able to handle but with the
你能处理，但与
temptation it will always provide a way
诱惑它总会提供一种方式
of escape boy that's that that's
逃脱男孩的那就是那个
reassuring news that's what we need to
令人放心的消息是我们需要的
understand is as God's people all right
理解是上帝的子民可以
good now I want to come back to this I
好现在我想回到这个我
don't want to forget anything else from
不想忘记其他任何事情
that chapter Julie that you want to
朱莉你想要的章节
highlight for us I just closed it yeah
为我们突出显示我刚关闭它是的
um I just highlighted a couple other
嗯我刚刚突出了其他几个
things um I just liked what I said about
事我嗯，我只是喜欢我所说的
fretting and said fretting inhibits
微动， 并说微动抑制
people from serving the Lord effectively
有效地为主服务的人
because it completely distracts their
因为它完全分散了他们的注意力
mind from the things of the Lord okay if
从耶稣的事放在心上没关系，如果
yeah I'm gonna testimony of that I think
是的，我想要证明我的想法
yeah and just talking about practically
是的，只是谈论几乎
how you exercise you need to exercise
你怎么锻炼你需要运动
control over the tongue and over your
在舌头和上控制你的
thoughts and so that they become
思想，使他们成为
pleasing to God and just you wait that
神所喜悦的， 只是你等那么
view of like you are just seeing
像你刚才看到的观点
pleasing the Lord just but that's the
取悦主，但那就是
new concept to me that you please the
新的概念对我来说，你喜欢的
Lord in order to find joy rather than
主为了找到快乐而不是
you do what is right yeah feelings
你做的是对的，是的感情
comments yes rather than searching for
评论是， 而不是搜索
the hand because we've been doing it yes
手，因为我们已经做了肯定的
yeah good and just going to the
是的好，只是要去
sanctuary I love that part where it says
庇护所我喜欢它所说的 那一部分
in the Psalms I didn't understand why
在诗篇中，我不明白为什么
all this was happening until I went and
这一切都发生了，直到我去了
had basically God's perspective you know
你知道基本上是上帝的观点
yeah
是啊
yeah so those are the elastics the whole
是的所以那些是整体的弹性
is yo just think you know what is true
哟，只是觉得你知道什么是真的
and controlling the thoughts those
并控制那些想法
distractions that have come in that we
分散于我们身上的分心
talked about we're so prevalent in your
谈到我们在你们中如此普遍
own devotional life or is so hard for to
自己的灵修生活或者是这么辛苦
focus on even reading God's Word or even
甚至专注于阅读上帝的话语
our prayer time together it's just just
我们的祷告时间在一起，它只是刚刚
a wonderful blessing from the Lord to
一个美好的祝福，从主到
walk through even a passage like
走过甚至像一个段落
Philippians 4 about in times of anxiety
腓立比人4在焦虑的时候
Lehner requests before the Lord and in
勒纳 在主面前 请求
seeking Him but also it says there to
寻求他，但也说它
think on what is true and all those
思考什么是真实的和所有这些
different things there how we get those
不同的事情我们如何得到那些
into practice well we saw some important
在实践中我们看到了一些重要的
things about how the scriptures address
关于经文如何解决的事情
depression and also how God used his
抑郁症以及上帝如何使用他的
word in this case to help Julie make
在这种情况下， 帮助朱莉做的话
significant progress she's thinking
她正在思考的重大进展
differently and she's thinking
不同，她在想
differently about God and about the
不同于上帝和关于
circumstances in her life in the next
在她的生活中的情况下
clip that we'll see it's six weeks after
剪辑，我们会在六周后看到它
that it's week 10 of counseling so this
它的辅导10周所以这
will be the first 16 minutes of that
将是第16 分钟
tenth and what turns out to be the final
第十，结果是最后的结果
session so let's take a look at that our
会议让我们来看看我们的
counseling sessions when it comes to
咨询会议
your homework and and Julie I know it's
你的作业和朱莉我都知道
been especially hard for you to kind of
尤为你很难 种
keep up with some of that homework on a
跟上一些功课上
week to week basis but as time has gone
周复一周的基础，但随着时间的流逝
on
上
you've just responded to that really
你刚刚回答了这个问题
well and I'm just grateful for the Lord
好吧，我只是感谢主
for what changes he's brought about in
什么改变了他带来的
your life and Joe I see you as a much
你的生活和乔我认为你很多
more caring and compassionate husband
更有爱心和富有同情心的丈夫
now so I'm very thankful for that as
所以我现在很为 非常 感谢
well this particular appointment and in
以及这个特别的任命和
our last appointment we I had actually
我们最后的约会，我实际上
mentioned to you that I was considering
提到你我正在考虑
graduating you out of counseling because
毕业于你的辅导因为
you had progressed so well but I felt
你进步得那么好，但我觉得
that we needed at least have one
我们至少需要一个
additional appointment in order to
为了额外的预约
fine-tune everything for the future all
为未来所有人微调一切
right just to make sure that everything
只是为了确保一切
is right everything is going well and so
是正确的一切都很顺利，因此
let me ask just a couple of general
让我问几个将军
question
题
in order to get at that and then I want
为了得到那个然后我想要
to go to the Word of God again and kind
再次回到神的话语，善良
of wrap things up there Joe if you were
如果你在那里包装乔
to describe for me some of the things
为我描述一些事情
that God has done over the past several
上帝 过去几次 所做的事
weeks of counseling in your life the
你生命中的几周辅导
changes that he is brought how would you
他带来的变化你会怎样
describe it I think first of all would
描述它我认为首先会
be described as a greater understanding
被描述为更大的理解
of what it means to be a man after God's
在上帝之后成为一个男人意味着什么
own heart as we talked about in the very
我们谈论的是自己的心
first session that is the core issue
第一次会议是核心问题
that I've grown to understand is it's
我已经逐渐明白了是不是
not in her behavior or her lack of
不是她的行为或她缺乏
ability to please me that my
能够取悦我的
satisfaction and my joy are found but
满意和我的喜悦被发现但是
it's in that I am more in love with
它在，我越来越 爱
Jesus Christ and more satisfied with him
耶稣基督对他更满意
more than anything and out of that that
比什么都重要
love and that joy that flows from that
爱和从那里流出的快乐
that maintains a constancy with or
用或维持一个恒定
without her her joy or her obedience or
没有她的快乐或她的顺从或
anything else and that's as I pursue
其他任何东西都是我追求的
Christ like Paul said so I want her to
像保罗一样的基督说我想要她
pursue me in following me that is my my
追求我在下面我说，是我的我的
greatest thing that I've learned in this
我在这方面学到的最棒的东西
time is just to to gear my mind in my
时间只是为了让我的思绪在我心中
life more in obeying Christ and fixing
生活更多地服从基督和固定
my eyes on him more than on her and what
我对他的眼睛不仅仅是关注她，还有什么
she's failing to do okay that's good
她没有做好，这很好
where would you say in relationship to
在那里你会在关系说
how you treat the priority the ministry
你如何对待事工的优先事项
and the priority of your relationship to
和你的关系的优先权
Julie where has can you give me some
朱莉你能在哪里给我一些
concrete examples on how that has has
如何已经有具体的例子
changed yeah I think number one what I
改变是的我认为我是第一
just said the priority of Christ making
刚才说基督的优先级进行
sure that that priority is established
确保确定优先级
from from very first of the day I'm
从我第一天开始
spending time with him in his word I'm
和他在一起的时间和我在一起
spending time with him in prayer there
和他一起在那里祷告
is an accountability that I have
是一种责任，我有
the my elders there at the church and
我的长老在教堂和那里
that being established has really given
正在建立的确实给了
the life to where my other priorities
生活到我的其他优先事项
should be underneath that and of course
应该是下面的课程和
after that would would definitely be my
之后那肯定是我的
wife and we found a baby that we're
妻子和我们发现了一个宝贝，我们是
going to be having it's my next priority
将它作为我的下一个优先事项
and and that has been like I said before
就像我之前说过的那样
a total war you know between ministry
在事工之间你所知道的全面战争
and my wife and how that is handled
和我的妻子以及如何处理
there but these times have helped me put
有，但这些时间帮我把
her in that priority position right
她在优先位置的权利
after my walk with the Lord is my
在我与主同行之后是我的
relationship with her if I can fail in
如果我能失败，与她的关系
ministry I can fail it at everything
我可以在一切事情上失败
else but I cannot fail yes in my love
否则我不能在我的爱中失败
for Christ and I had relationship with
因为基督和我有关系
my why yeah and that's pretty clear to
我为什么是的，这很清楚
Paul talks to Timothy Arian 473 that's
保罗与蒂莫西·阿里安473 谈话
one of the qualifications of an elder is
老人的资格之一是
that if an elder is going to be a part
如果一个老人要成为一个部分
of the ministry of the church then he's
然后他就是教会的事工
got to have his relationship to his wife
得与妻子建立了关系
and his children in order first
和他的孩子先排序
so there's gives you a little bit of
所以这是给你 的 一点点
clue as to what the priority should be
关于优先级应该是什么的线索
before he turns around and has an
在他转身并有一个
effective ministry in the church as well
在教会中也有效的事工
so that's good that's really good all
所以这真的很好
right all right looking back as well Joe
好吧， 好吧回想起乔
let me ask you this if there is or if
如果有或有，请让我问你
there has been a change in terms of your
你的方面发生了变化
own heart desires I think I've picked up
自己心中的欲望我想我已经接受了
on some of this from what you've already
从你已经有的一些
said but can you describe for me a
说不过你可以描述我
little bit more for example you remember
多一点，例如，你还记得
in the earlier sessions you talked about
在之前的会议中你谈到过
your expectations of what Julie should
你对朱莉的期望
do in relationship to this ministry and
做关系，该部和
the women's ministry this kind of thing
妇女事工就是这样的事情
that kind of thing and you realized
那种事，你意识到了
through counseling that that really
通过咨询真的
stemmed from a certain desire in your
源于你的某种欲望
heart that just kind of overwhelmed how
心脏，只是那种不知所措如何
has that desire changed what was the
有这种愿望改变了什么
desire originally and I think the desire
最初的欲望，我认为的愿望
was multifaceted on one front it was the
在一个方面是多方面的，它是
public public appearance desire where
公众面貌欲望在哪里
you want your wife to
你想要你的妻子
fit that role that you want her to fit
适合你希望她适合的角色
in the local church you want her to
在当地教会你想让她
fulfill those responsibilities and those
履行那些责任和那些责任
expectations that you have for her to
你对 她的 期望
fulfill in ministry in the church at the
履行部在 该教堂
same time you want to be able to model
同时你想要能够建模
what that godly relationship looks like
这种敬虔的关系是什么样的
and you know it's so hard to be able to
你知道它是如此难以能
stand in the pulpit or to be able to
站在讲台上，或者能够
counsel people when you know your own
在你了解自己的时候为人们提供咨询
life with your wife is a wreck or really
和你妻子的生活是一个残骸或真的
struggling and so I think desires as far
挣扎， 所以我认为欲望到目前为止
as just performance-based desires
只是基于表现的欲望
selfish desires my needs being met my
自私的欲望满足了我的需要
expectations being fulfilled on my
我的期望得到满足
pleasure is being satisfied yes those
快乐是满足的是那些
desires have shifted more towards a my
欲望已转向更多我的
desires being fulfilled and satisfied in
欲望得到满足和满意的
Jesus Christ and not so focused as far
耶稣基督并没有那么专注
as on those what you called ruling
就像你所谓的裁决一样
desires idolatrous desires that can be
渴望偶像崇拜欲望
so controlling no needs not being met or
所以控制不需要不被满足或
other things there and God has created
上帝创造了其他的东西
us in such a way we have to worship
我们以这样的方式 ，我们必须崇拜
something and that's the way our hearts
什么，这就是我们的心
are are bent
是弯曲的
we can't help as human beings and when
我们无法作为人类和时间的帮助
we worship the wrong things that's what
我们崇拜的是错误的东西
ends up becoming our idols of our heart
最终成为我们心中的偶像
it can be power prestige or wanting
它可以是声望或想要的
someone to treat us in a certain way or
有人以某种方式对待我们 或
be a certain way
是某种方式
anything that's desirable can turn into
任何可取的东西都可以变成
a idolatrous desire and it becomes more
一个偶像崇拜的欲望，它变得更多
important than God and I think that's
比上帝重要，我想是的
especially true let me speak to you from
尤其是让我跟你说话
as a pastor to a pastor because after
因为作为一个后 牧师牧师
all the training that a pastor goes
所有牧师的训练
through all that's focus and interest
通过所有的重点和兴趣
and making sure they're delivering the
并确保他们提供
Word of God and doing the ministry
上帝的话语和做事工
properly and pouring their lives in the
正确地倾注他们的生命
minute and to other people that become
分钟和其他成为的人
such a focus that even though in and of
这样的焦点，即使在和
itself that's a very legitimate desire I
本身这是一个非常合法的愿望我
mean I want to be a good pastor but that
意思是我想成为一名优秀的牧师但那
desire can be greater than I want to be
欲望大于我想成为
God's kind of man in other words that
换句话说，上帝是那种人
desire is elevated and it becomes an
欲望升高，成为一种欲望
illegitimate desire and it becomes an
非法的欲望，它变成了一个
idolatrous desire even though originally
即使是最初的偶像崇拜欲望
it started off as a very legitimate
它起初是非常合法的
desire all right and then becomes more
渴望所有权利然后变得更多
important than being God's kind of man
比作为上帝的那种人更重要
God's being God's kind of husband God's
上帝是上帝的丈夫上帝的
kind of father that kind of thing and
父亲那种事和那种
now everything else are so what started
现在一切都是如此开始
off really good years of training and
真的好多年的训练和
focus gradually gradually goes like this
重点渐渐逐渐如此
and all of a sudden now we're getting
现在我们突然间得到了
angry frustrated confused with our wife
生气沮丧与我们的妻子 混淆
when she's not responding the way that I
当她没有回应我的方式时
expect her to respond all right no I
指望她回应 没事人无我
know that because I'm a human I'm a
知道， 因为我是一个人，我是一个人
father and I'm a husband and I'm a man
父亲和我是丈夫，我是男人
so I know that that that that's true
所以我知道那是真的
that's why I have to make sure my
这就是为什么我必须确保我的
expectations of life my thoughts are
我的想法是对生活的期望
wedded to the Word of God day in and day
日复一日坚持上帝的话语
out that has to be that's good all right
这一切都是好的
Julie let me ask you all right
朱莉让我问你没事吧
originally the two of you came in with a
原来你们两个进来了
presentation problem of depression we
抑郁症的表现问题我们
found out since then that there are a
从那时起发现有一个
lot more complicated issues a swirl
更复杂的问题是一个漩涡
around this than what we originally
围绕这个比我们原来的
thought
思想
and God has certainly brought about some
而且上帝确实带来了一些
really great changes in your life we've
我们的生活真的发生了很大的变化
seen you deal with some really
看到你真的处理了一些
substantive hard issues that were hard
难以解决的实质性难题
to deal with tell me how Julie has
处理告诉我朱莉有多少
changed from where she was back when she
她从她回来的地方改变了
first started coming into counseling and
第一次开始进入咨询和
where she is now hmm um I think when we
她现在在哪里嗯嗯，我认为，当我们
first came in for counseling I wanted
我首先进入了我想要的咨询
you to take away my my feelings and make
你要带走我的感情并做出让步
it better in yeah um we're looking more
它是更好的，是的，我们看起来更多
for you know not understanding why I'm
因为你知道不明白我为什么
depressed in and I'm on the surface
郁闷，我在表面上
level I think coming out of just from a
等级，我认为只是出自一个
medical standpoint and being on a drug
医学立场和吸毒
and in and not understanding that from
并且不理解来自
that perspective and I think it's been
这个观点，我认为它已经存在
really helpful to go through first of
真的很有帮助，先通过
all just trusting God has been a huge
所有只是相信上帝是一个巨大的
impact where understanding the character
理解角色的地方
of God and they
上帝和他们
he's not you know aloof even if I don't
即使我不知道，他也不是你知道的超然
feel like he's accessible I don't feel
觉得他很容易接近我感觉不到
like praying or I don't feel like these
喜欢祈祷或者我不喜欢这些
things it doesn't change the fact that
事情并没有改变这一事实
he's sovereign and that he's in control
他是主权者，他掌控着自己
and that he's a loving God and he's in
并且他是一位慈爱的上帝而且他在
charge of absolutely everything in I
在我身上绝对收费
think just I've grown a lot and just
我想我刚刚成长了很多
having an elevated view of of who he is
对自己是谁有一个更高的看法
and when you focus on the person and
当你专注于人和
character of God and in Christ and what
上帝和在基督里的 品格 和什么
he's done for us and that we do have all
他为我们做了，我们做到了
spiritual blessings in heavenly places
精神祝福在天上
in Christ and you know that he's a
在基督里，你知道他是一个
compassionate eye priest and he and
富有同情心的牧师和他和他
sympathising our weaknesses and anyway
无论如何， 同情我们的弱点
it just puts that has really helped to
它只是说，这真的有帮助
put my whole life in problems into
把我的一生都放在了问题中
perspective as far as I was very
观点至于我很
self-focused and so I didn't want to get
自我专注，所以我不想得到
up in the morning because it was all
因为这一切都在早上起来
about my perceive my perception of my
关于我的感知我对我的看法
problems and not focusing on what was
问题而不是专注于什么
true and true of Who I am in Christ and
真实的我是谁在基督里的真实，
who God is and what I'm called to and
上帝是谁， 我被召唤和
the privilege in the ministry of being
在存在的事工中的特权
called dope to where I've been called
叫做涂料到我被称为的地方
him to be made to a godly pastor and I
他将成为一位敬虔的牧师和我
know just seeing the world through
知道只是看透世界
through God's perspective and getting
通过上帝的观点和得到
getting out of asking you know why me
离开问你知道我为什么
and and what's going on I also learned a
而且发生了什么我也学到了一个
lot about and didn't want to be
关于并且不想成为
submissive to um what God had called me
顺从上帝所称的我
to do as a wife and I wanted to do
做一个妻子和我想做的事
things my own way and and trying to get
事情我自己的方式， 并试图得到
happiness rather than pursuing the Lord
幸福而不是追求主
and allowing him to be the full source
并允许他成为完整的来源
of that that joy and even that tree that
那种喜悦， 甚至那棵树
we drew where you know here I'm one tree
我们画了你知道的地方我是一棵树
and I really want to be this tree but I
我真的想成为这棵树，但我
wanted to jump from branch to branch
我想从一个分支跳到另一个分支
instead of like squirrels do this I want
而不是喜欢松鼠这样做我想要的
to be this tree but I want to be this
成为这棵树，但我想成为这样
tree my own way how I
树我自己的方式我怎么样
I want to get there you know I want the
我想到达那里你知道我想要的
circumstances and I want Joe to line up
情况，我希望乔排队
in a way that will please event me
以某种方式取悦 我的活动
rather than truly focusing on Christ and
而不是真正专注于基督和
and seeking to please him and so I think
并试图取悦他，所以我想
that's probably the major yeah good then
那可能是主要的，那么好
now can you safely say that that was
现在可以安全地说那就是
back about a fourth of fifth session
回到第五届会议的四分之一
that we spent together can you say
我们一起度过的你能说吗？
safely say that when realizing the route
在实现路线时安全地说
idolatrous desires are ruling in your
拜偶像的欲望在你的统治中占有一席之地
heart at that particular time that you
那个特定时刻的心，你
before the Lord have repented of those
在主悔改之前
you've seen those as sinful desires and
你已经把那些视为罪恶的欲望了
expectations and and now your desire is
期望和现在你的愿望
to put on yeah doing things God's Way
换上耶做事神之路
and being God's kind of wife and mother
并且是上帝的妻子和母亲
and you know that really helped us to
而你知道这对我们有帮助
and continuing on after that to redefine
然后继续重新定义
repentance for me that it's not just
忏悔对我而言，这不仅仅是
feeling bad about it and wanting to
感觉不好这件事，并希望
change but it's truly turning yes to
改变，但它真的转向了
where you died I totally see that I'm
在你去世的地方我完全看到了我
wrong in you know and that I desired to
错在你知道的和我想要
do the right thing not just feeling
做正确的事不只是感觉
guilty about doing there oh yeah yeah so
在那里做有罪哦，是的，是的
that's really good I think that is that
这真的很好我认为就是这样
it that is so critical and I and I like
它是如此关键，我和我喜欢
your analogy of jumping from branch to
你从分支到跳跃的类比
branch and picking up on that too
分支并接受它
because I think a lot of people want to
因为我觉得很多人都想
do that they want to just change merely
这样做他们只想改变
the behavioral things and of course we
行为的事情当然是我们
don't want to ignore those those are
不想忽视那些
very very important but just you know
非常重要，但只是你知道
giving you better principles on getting
给你更好的原则
up in the morning or giving you better
早上起来还是给你更好的
principles on how to study the Bible or
关于如何学习圣经的原则
how not to be depressed sort of often
怎么不经常郁闷
handles just behavioral characteristics
处理行为特征
and I want you to see that there's
我想让你看到那里
something that fuels that all of that
能激发所有这一切的东西
run fruit and we've got to change the
运行水果，我们已经得到了改变
fuel and so that it's you have good
燃料，这样你就有了好处
godly desires that motivate you in the
虔诚的欲望激励着你
right way in order to honor and please
正确的方式，以荣誉和取悦
him
他
and I think that in years into the
而且我认为在几年内进入了
future because you've gone through this
未来因为你经历过这个
and you this is something that has been
而你这是一直存在的事情
sustained for a couple of years in your
持续了几年在你的
life you'll still probably have a human
生活你仍然可能有一个人
weakness whether it be a weakness of the
弱点是否是一个弱点
flesh or whatever however willing to
肉体或任何其他愿意的东西
describe it to go back into that
形容它回到那个
depression but I think that identifying
抑郁，但我认为，识别
what your thinking was that led you to
你的想法是什么导致你
that or your desires were and your
那个或你的愿望是和你的
expectations how your conscience was
期待你的良心是怎样的
functioning at that time that we've
我们当时正在运作
talked about will enable you to cut that
谈到将使你削减它
short so that you don't go back into
简短，这样你就不会再回去了
that with severity that you have in the
你有严重程度的
past and then that's what I'm hoping for
过去然后那就是我所希望的
and then some of the passages that
然后一些通道， 用以
you've memorized as part of homework and
你已经记住了作为家庭作业的一部分
the two of you have worked on together I
你们两个一起有工作在I
mean those should be already helped to
意味着那些应该已经有所帮助
you even if I'm not around or in your
你，即使我不在你身边或你的
life or some other pastor or counselor
生活或其他一些牧师或辅导员
or someone's not should be already help
或某人不应该已经帮助
what you were going to say something
你要说的东西
well I think I was just a cream okay
好吧，我想我只是一个奶油好吧
okay one thing I did I would I didn't
好吧，我做了一件事我不会
want to say is that has been fun neat to
我想说的是一直很有趣
see for me I think one of the most
看到我，我认为最多
convicting things is when he's serving
在他服务的时候定罪
like Christ that's the most convicting
像基督一样，这是最有罪的
thing I think I've really found um that
事我觉得我真的找到了那个
you I see a picture of who Christ really
你我看到了一幅基督真实的画面
is he's serving that way and one that
在他服务于该方式，另一种
makes yes Christ that much more
使基督更加美好
attractive and I think that's been the
有吸引力，我认为这是
biggest catalyst for helping me to even
帮助我平衡的最大催化剂
grow in my love for God and his
在我对上帝和他的 爱中成长
character is when I see that and Joe and
当我看到那个和Joe和
it's been a big um growth yes few weeks
这几周是一个很大的增长
well the end of a counseling case that
那个咨询案的结束了
went well there's always great joy in
过得好，总是很开心
that the last thing that always happens
总是发生 的最后一件事
in counseling cases where there's been
在咨询情况下，有一直
this change where God has done what only
这种改变只有上帝做了什么
he can do he's changed hearts through
他可以做到他已经改变了心灵
his word is the wonderful time of Prayer
他的话是祷告的美好时光
where can
哪里可以
slurs and council e's are just praising
诽谤和议会e只是赞美
God for what he's done and giving things
上帝为他所做的和给予的东西
all the glory goes to God when he
所有荣耀归于上帝的时候
changes hearts through his word and
通过他的话和改变心灵
that's really exciting it's also
这真的很令人兴奋
exciting in situations like that because
在这种情况下令人兴奋，因为
when you're working with somebody who's
当你和某个人一起工作的时候
a leader in ministry there's there's
事工的领导者就是那里
there's so much at stake there you know
你知道那里有太多的利害关系
because not only is it this this couple
因为这对夫妻不仅如此
but it's it's there their ministry to a
但它是在那里他们的事工
large degree and that's been a great
很大程度上，这是一个伟大的
privilege over the years to see in our
多年来我们的特权
counseling room God do that same thing
咨询室上帝做同样的事情
equip leaders in ministry and spouses
装备部长和配偶领导人
and to change and to honor God so that's
并改变并尊重上帝
exciting stuff all the way around well
一路上令人兴奋的东西
very good well that concludes our movie
非常好，我们的电影结束了
for a Saturday afternoon
星期六下午
you
您